# H. ÇAĞRI TOPÇU

#### **TECHNICAL PRODUCT MANAGER**

Email : hctopcu@gmail.com

Date of Birth : 1985

Linkedin : <u>linkedin.com/in/hctopcu</u>

+90 (532) 566 15 26

Kadıköy / Istanbul - Turkey

# **Summary**

I'm a technical product manager working with multiple development squads to improve cross-squad communications, helping to interpolate business needs and create technical solutions. Driven by the desire to solve problems and exceed business value.

Working on a \$M budget company with 25+ people serving 100+ stakeholders.

With strong communication skills and a good grasp of the business domain, I work with other product managers and product owners and stakeholders to develop product strategies.

Having more than 10 years of experience in software development; I also take a role as a solution architect, helping create better-performing products. Able to understand tech trends, see how they impact the roadmap, and how they drive innovation.

Able to understand technical challenges and make educated trade-offs with the teams.

I am looking forward to connecting with you further to discuss my qualifications and my excitement to work with.

# Skill Highlights

- Product Development
- Product Roadmap
- Product Shaping
- User Stories Planning & Designing
- Customer Satisfaction
- Product Auditing
- Business Strategy
- Market Research

- Solution Architecture
- Product Delivery
- Coding & Testing
- Budget Management & Cost Optimization
- Agile Methodologies
- Innovative
- Decision Maker
- · Problem Solver



# Technical Proficiencies

- PHP: Laravel, Symphony
- .NET: C#.NET, .NET Core
- Cloud Architecture:

Amazon AWS, Microsoft Azure Google Cloud CCS, Object Storge Block Storage, CDN, MQ Cloud Networking

- Load Balancing,
  Forward & Reverse
  Proxies, Applicaation Firewalls
- · Caching Stategies

#### DB:

SqlServer, SQL on Azure SqlServer on Linux MySQL, MariaDB PosgreSQL. MongoDB

- ElasticSearch
- · Redis, Redis Cluster, Memcache
- Web Services, Soap, WCF, REST, Postman, SoapUI
- Jira (Cloud and On Premise Administration)

# **Experience**

## Scotty

Turkey • 07.2021 to Present

#### **Digital Product Manager**

Scotty is founded in 2017 to bring an alternative solution with their elite motorcycle fleet in order to save thousands of customers' precious commute time who suffer from Istanbul's heavy traffic problem. Scotty Delivery focuses on logistics and premium LMD leveraging the company's field experience and agile fleet.

I've joined Scotty to team up with a new product team and help bring Scotty's delivery vision into a product for the company's logistics operations.

### My main responsibilities are:

- Follow the domain's current and future trends, demands, and needs.
- Work with stakeholders, departments, and accounts to create a manageable program.
- Keep in touch with stakeholders to cross-update and keep in sync.
- Come up with a feature list and product roadmap for a new product.

Create the backlog for features required.

- Involve in product development as a product owner and scrum master for a new team.
- Manage the backlog, and keep track of the frequent priority changes and scope updates.

Create wireframes, file requirements, and technical documents.

Refine backlog with designers, front-end, back-end, and mobile developers, and DevOps in the team.

- Facilitate Scrum rituals and help the team improve efficiency
- Communicate with integrated active accounts/companies to help improve their business.

# **Gordion Technology**

Turkey • 11.2017 to 07.2021

#### **Technical Product Manager, Business Development Manager**

Gordion Teknoloji is a technology company started with a vision to bring innovative and complete solution to travel business. Gordios its main product; is subset of tens of independent sub-projects collectively act as an all-in-one ERP solution. Central hub used by thousands of users in hundreds of agencies, corporate partners, call centers and web sites, serving inventories not only generated by its own several backoffice products but also tens of provider integrations.

#### I've joined the team 1 year prior to the launch.

- Took an active role in completing and polishing the products and making them fit for live.
- Work with the stakeholders and sale channels to see their current needs and define requirements. Research for future requirements that will aid the customers' processes.
- Work with cross-functional teams to come up with a detailed business solution, ensure optimization in usability and performance.
- Create technical solutions to solve problems and to improve the products.
- Conduct the product lifecycle and help teams eliminate any roadblocks.
- Aid the squads in any impediments that might affect the process and be sure the solution meets the market needs.
- Identify any cost savings and/or performance improvement points throughout the projects.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.
- Seek out and meet new partners with business stakeholders for possible partnership solutions.

## Athena Technology

Turkey • 09.2013 to 11.2017

#### **Software Development Manager**

Athena Teknoloji is a startup company aims on creating tailormade solutions to travel industry.

- Took a role on kickstarting the company.
- Recruiting and operations management.
- Directly managed the development team of both inhouse and outsource resources.
- Worked with the clients to define their requirements.
- Conducted and worked hands on in the projects' development cycles.
- Maintained the success on tight budgets and deadlines.

## Mynet A.S.

Turkey • 08.2011 to 09.2013

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Mynet is the biggest portal of the country, serving multiple content sites to visitors.

Sites like Finance and Sport are the #1 rank in their respective user bases.

- Worked as a part of the development team, responsible for maintaining several infrastructural and portal projects.
- Leaded multiple renovation projects porting and rewriting old systems in modern platforms capable of handling over tens of thousands requests per-second as of 2012
- Lead developer for infrastructure projects like AdServer (Advertisement server) and Market (payment gateway for the whole Mynet ecosystem.)
- Lead developer for Spor (sports portal) and Finans (finance portal)
- Actively developing on multiple platforms such as ASP, ASP.NET, PHP, NodeJS.

## Müzik Market Ltd

Turkey • 04.2008 to 08.2011

### **Software Developer**

Mydukkan.com company's e-commerce site on providing products for musicians is the lead website on their domain. Partnered with multiple distributors using in house developed logistics, stock management, CRM, process management products.

- Worked as a Software Developer maintaining an improving inhouse systems.
- ASP, ASP.NET, PHP

## **Education**

## **Anadolu University**

Eskisehir - Turkey • 2008

Computer Engineering (Eng)

# **Ortaca High School**

Mugla - Turkey • 2001 - 2003

# Denizli Science High School

Denizli - Turkey 2000 - 2001

## **Hobbies**

## **Scuba Diving**

PADI Master Scuba Diver Trainer, Emergency First Response Instructor 2019 - Present

# **3D Printing**

Designing and printing 3D objects for fun using Fusion 360. I own a custom made and an Ender 3v2 printers

# Language

# **English**

## **Turkish**

C1

Native